Emma Coughlin

5557 40th Ave S

Minneapolis, MN 55417

JinJooLee126@gmail.com

Summary of experience:

After working in the service industry for over 15 years, I have completed one of the Full Stack Developer bootcamp programs through the University of Minnesota Continuing Education's curriculum. I received my certificate in August of 2022. As such, I have a wide variety of skills given my many years in customer service and managing teams in different settings. I am looking forward to taking on new challenges in the developer field, with a focus on front end web development.

Education:

Minneapolis Community and Technical College

1501 Hennepin Ave South Minneapolis, MN 55403

Associate of Arts. Attended 2009-2013.

• Dean's List 2009-2013. Awarded to students who complete 12 credits or more in a semester with a GPA of 3.0 (out of 4.0) or higher for the semester.

University of Minnesota – College of Continuing and Professional Studies

1420 Eckles Ave Saint Paul, MN 55108

Completed online course running from February 2022 – August 2022.

- Proficient in: CSS, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, GitLab, GitHub, Git, Node.js, SQL and several other coding related applications.
- GitHub: https://github.com/jinjoolee1
- Portfolio: https://jinjoolee1.github.io/new-portfolio/

Employment History:

<u>Carbone's Pizzeria Minneapolis, MN July 2008 – July 2012</u>

· Hostess/Server.

I continued working in food service and I spend more time with my customers. This restaurant can be very busy at times, and I felt my skills at my previous job helped me succeed even more in this

job. I handled phones, took orders, solved problems for customers regarding their satisfaction and I have more face-to-face time with my customers. I learned how to keep customers satisfied and further develop my service skills.

Pizza Lucé July 2012 – August 2018

· Support staff/Supervisor/Front of House Manager. Hopkins, Richfield, Saint Paul, Uptown. (2012-2018).

I began working at Pizza Lucé in Richfield at the end of July 2012 when the store first opened. I worked as full support staff which included: host, cashier, food runner, busser, barback and phones job titles. I have learned how to multitask very well at this job and I feel I have expanded my customer service skills at this job. I have been able to flex all of my FOH skills in throughout the years and I have thoroughly mastered all of these positions. I returned to Pizza Lucé Saint Paul in December of 2018 to rejoin the support staff team and I have become a key member of the team not only because of my strengths in service but also because of my previous manager experience.

• Expeditor. Hopkins, Richfield, Saint Paul, Uptown (April 2013-present).

Expeditors play a key role in Luce operations. They are the last line of defense before the food goes out to the customers and act as quality control. All managers are trained in full expeditor responsibilities, although expeditors are usually cooks. They are the best multitaskers and need to have a good attitude to do well. Responsibilities include plating food, boxing up delivery/pick-up orders, making sure food comes out of the ovens in a timely manner, keeping an eye on ticket times and making sure the food looks great.

Front of House supervisor. Richfield & Hopkins. (April 2016- August 2017).

I was promoted to front of house supervisor in April of 2016 after being passed up twice at the Saint Paul store. I applied for the position at Richfield and was offered the front of house supervisor job. This was the preliminary to becoming a salaried manager. I performed the usual support staff duties while operating as the supervisor and handled all operations/admin work during my shifts. I learned how to manage people, write schedules, problem solve when there were shortages in staffing, manage the safety team and built up some good experience running shifts before becoming a full salaried manager.

• Front of House/Bar Manager. Uptown Minneapolis (August 2017 – September 2018).

I was put into my full Restaurant Manager position in August of 2017 at Pizza Luce Uptown and have been holding the title ever since then. My job responsibilities include: operations, running shifts, being in charge of the front of house team, (writing their schedules, food and beverage meetings, accolades, discipline, hiring, training, reviews, etc), bar ordering/inventory, running the safety team within the store and the events/street team within the store and running my individual store's social media accounts. My department has gone from 4th in the company to 1st in company secret shops.

Black Sheep Coal Fired Pizza (2018).

Assistant General Manager Black Sheep Coal Fire Pizza (September 2018 – December 2018).

I left Pizza Lucé for three months and tried my hand with a new company that I believed had a similar concept to Lucé. My responsibilities at this job were split directly with the general manager and I

was given the title of assistant general manager during my time with Black Sheep. My duties included basic operations (running the floor, managing and controlling labor, handling customer feedback and dealing with the external delivery service), beer/liquor ordering, supporting the restaurant, general maintenance and upkeep of the restaurant, food/beverage inventory and ordering. It was a combination of the many jobs I worked at Pizza Lucé with some added kitchen/BOH responsibilities. At the end of the day, Black Sheep was not a supportive environment for me and I had to make the decision to leave for my physical, mental and emotional health.

Zen Box Izakaya (2019-2022)

Front of House Manager (July 2019 – September 2022)

I joined the front of house team at Zen Box Izakaya in July of 2019. After several rounds of applying for supervisory roles at Pizza Lucé, I decided to end my employment with them in favor of something that was more suited to my skills. I had also been looking to work for a small business and Zen Box was the perfect fit. I reported to my manager, the assistant GM and the owners, John Ng and Lina Goh on a daily basis. I learned a lot from this team and worked very closely with back of house leads/managers as well to ensure quality service in all aspects of the restaurants. I was responsible for inventory, running the service floor during service hours, handling guests, writing schedules, discipline/accolades among staff and working as a regular team member during service hours. Zen Box was truly a hybrid of managing a team but also being a key part of the team.

References:

<u>Scott Schierman – General Manager Pizza Lucé Richfield</u> 218-343-1617

<u>Charlie Sam – Director of Hospitality/Beverage Manager Grand Casino Minnesota</u> 320-279-0867

<u>Aidan Hybertson – Shift Lead Zen Box Izakaya</u> 612-597-4949

<u>Mike Brock – Full Stack Developer and Colleague</u> 612-704-7568